ABUBAKKAR

A self-motivated, creative, and a proven team player, I have more than two years of professional experience in variety of roles and responsibilities in Front End Development building and managing small- and large-scale web applications. I have hands on experience working with technologies Angular, JavaScript, React.js, Asp.Net Core, Angular Material Design, CSS 3, HTML 5, SASS, Bootstrap4 and extensive experience consuming REST Web Services at client end.

CONTACT

+923421898417
abubakkarmit@gmail.co
m
LinkedIn/abubakkarmit
GitHub/abubakkariiui
Peronal Website/ link

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNAZ — Full Stack Developer

JAN 2021 - MAR 2022

Unaz has been designed to keep everything in one place - a simple software management platform! Whether this company provides, legal services, other non-skilled services, it's also support fresh Graduate, its user-friendly design and smart automations streamline your daily process through technology. Asp.net core, PostgreSQL db, SQL Server db, SQLITE db, Angular 11, Html5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4, (Angular Ngxs Library).

Key Responsibilities:

| | Strong understanding of building web apps from scratch. |
|--|--|
| | Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability. |
| | Creating visually appealing web pages or interfaces using (HTML 5 / CSS 3 / Sass / |
| | Bootstrap / Foundation / Semantic UI / Angular Material Design). |
| | Modify current code according to client requirements. |
| | Migrated application from the Old static structure to advanced Angular 2 Front end |
| | Structure. |
| | Testing cross-browser, cross-platform, and/or cross-device compatibility for |
| | inconsistencies. |

Technologies: Asp.net Core (Web API), Angular 11(Ngxs), Bootstrap 4 and Angular Material Design.

Genesis Engineering — Angular Developer

MAR 2022 - PRESENT

Key Responsibilities:

| | Working as Project manager to talk with clients and get all the requirements. | | |
|--|--|--|--|
| | Creating visually appealing web pages or interfaces using (HTML 5 / CSS 3 / Sass / | | |
| | Bootstrap / Foundation / Semantic UI / Angular Material Design). | | |
| | Modify current code according to client requirements. | | |
| | Working with Jira, Slack, Bitbucket and Trello to manage the project. | | |
| Technologies: Angular 11(Ngxs), React Js, Bootstrap 4 and Angular Material | | | |
| Design. | | | |

EDUCATION

International Islamic University Islamabad, Bachelor in Software Engineering.

SEP 2017 - OCT 2021

PROJECTS

Shop management system: Online shop management system Application is under construction. Tools and Technologies: Asp.Net Core MVC, Angular 7, bootstrap 4, JWT (JSON Web Token). Backend Apis is deployed on heroku and Frontend is deployed on GitHub.

Planner (Note Web Application): An online Web application, covering all aspects of online data saving and accessing. Developing using React Js, Node Js, React Bootstrap.

STACK

Proficient: Angular (Ngxs), JavaScript, React.js (Redux), Bootstrap 4/5, Git, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Material Design,

Familiar: Node.js,Asp.Net Core (Web Api),Node Js, mongoose db

AWARDS

Certificate of Completion: Responsive Web Design (FreeCodeCamp)

Certificate of Completion: HTML Fundamentals (Solo Learn)

Certificate of Completion: React + Redux (Solo Learn)

Certificate of Completion: Responsive Web Design (Solo Learn)

Certificate of Completion: CSS3 (Solo Learn)

LANGUAGES

Urdu, native **English**, fluent **Pushto**, nati